(幽鬼丸)フゥ…。
(カブト)さすが 尾獣。
やはり 一筋縄じゃいかないか。
まあいい… 次の手を打つだけさ。
You actually tailed Samui.
You guys are pretty good.
(麟児)ふんっ… ん～っ！
Y-You...
(麟児)おい 無事かい？
(鬼霧)まぁ なんとか。
You're Naruto!
You tailed us! What's the big idea?!
Boss, the one on the right...
is Kakashi Hatake.
木ノ葉の連中は
近くにいねえみてえだな。
I know that!
状況が さっぱりだ。
Did the Hokage send you,
Kakashi Hatake?
(鬼霧)なぁ
さっきの大波は何だったんだ？
No, I came to ask you personally
それに
なんか鳴き声が聞こえたぜ。
about a request by Naruto Uzumaki
of the Hidden Leaf.
紅蓮さんたちは いったい何を？
Naruto Uzumaki?
たぶん
知らねえほうが身のためだな。
If you could hear him out
for just a while.
Isn't this a bit rude?
Stopping us en route to the summit
without any prior notice.
おう 牛頭 生きてたか。
I am fully aware of that.
(牛頭)あぁ… 紅蓮さんは？
No matter.
さあな。
(牛頭)お前なら捜せるはずだ。
You there, boy! Speak!
そうしたいのは山々だが➡
急に コウモリたちの反応が
途絶えちまった。
Sasuke...
正直 お手上げだ。
I want you to cancel
the disposal of Sasuke Uchiha!
どこへ行く気だ？
H-Hey, this isn't really the place...
(牛頭)ケガをしているかもしれない。
Are you still talking about that?!
You sure got guts.
お前 捜すったって… おい牛頭！
What are you saying?
I know it sounds ridiculous!
あっ！ チッ…。
But this is the only way
I know how to say it!
Sasuke is my friend!
やれやれ お熱なことで。
My friend's gonna get killed.
I can't just stand by and
let it happen!
(ナルト)イテテテ…。
クソッ！ ひでえ目に遭ったってばよ。
On top of that,
I don't want Sasuke to be
the cause of the Leaf and
Cloud Villages killing each other.
いったい どこまで流されたんだ。
I don't want my friends,
or the Cloud to fight for revenge!
そうだ！ アイツ…。
なんでアイツ 大蛇丸の仲間なんかと
一緒にいたんだってばよ…。
((いいか ソイツに ついて行け。
その手を離すんじゃねえぞ。
(うん))
もしかして オレのせいで…!?
I'm begging you!
クソッ… こんな霧！
I don't want us killing each other
out of vengeance anymore!
All Sasuke ever thought
about was revenge!
どこだ？ ここ。
He became obsessed with it
and that changed him.
Vengeance makes you go mad.
サスケ！
It turns you into someone
you don't recognize anymore.
(大蛇丸)ジャマしないでちょうだい。
I don't want anyone else
to become like Sasuke!
テメエ！ サスケをどうするつもりだ!?
I don't want the Leaf and Cloud Villages
to destroy each other!
(大蛇丸)フフフ…。
転生の儀式を始めるのよ。
That's why...
I have work to do,
so I'm going on ahead.
何だと!?
(大蛇丸)それが 彼の望み。
Please report to Kakashi Sensei
about the mission.
彼は力を… 私は彼を手に入れる。
Sure! You can count on me.
See you.
んなことさせっかよ！ サスケは
オレたちの所へ帰ってくるんだ!!
フフフ… バカめ！
彼は そんなこと望んでやしない。
Say Naruto...
それでも 思ってるヤツがいる所が
帰る場所なんだ！
You like Sakura, don't you?
What?!
オレは そう信じてる！
It was in a book.
本当に そうかしら。
When you're with someone you like,
you always smile.
You're like that.
Did you tell her how you feel?
うるせえ…。
How could I?
I'm a guy who couldn't even
keep my promise to her.
あなた 後悔するわよ。
Sai... Stay out of this.
うるせえ！ とぉ～っ!!
(カカシ)やめろ ナルト！
No. I can't just sit still either, Naruto.
(キバ)うわぁ！
フー…。 危ねえ。
カカシ先生。
お前なぁ
せっかく見つけてやったのに➡
We will dispose of Sasuke!
なんてことしやがんだよ！
でも 今ここに大蛇丸が…。
After that, you can stop the cycle.
ああん？
別に何も匂わねえけどな。
What a fool.
(カカシ)どうやら 幻覚のようだな。
We are in a hurry.
We've let you have your say.
えっ そんな…。
(赤丸)ワン！ ワン！
Lord Raikage...
(ヤマト)大丈夫かい？ ナルト。
(カカシ)無事 全員揃ったな。
The incident in which you tried
to obtain the Hyuga Byakugan
(シノ)だが問題がないわけじゃない。
ん？
is still unresolved on our side.
The Hidden Leaf swallowed
tears of blood and
見てくれ。
avoided fighting the Cloud,
who fueled the fires of war.
これは…。
先ほどから
急に様子が おかしくなった。
It's thanks to those noble sacrifices
that your people still exist.
方向感覚を やられている。
これでは偵察には使えない。
Please try not to forget that.
おい マジかよ!?
Right here and now,
this young ninja,
この異変は
霧が濃くなってからのようです。
no matter how awkwardly,
is bowing his head in his affection
for the Cloud and Leaf,
village and nation.
(カカシ)こっちも ナルトが幻覚を見た。
どうやら ただの霧じゃないねぇ。
Lord Raikage...
As one of the five Kage,
what do you think of this?
ナルト！ あの湖で何があった？
なんか すんげえ
でっけえカメが暴れてて➡
A ninja does not bow
his head so easily!
A ninja values action and strength!
ソイツと さっきのヤツらが戦ってた。
Concessions are forbidden
in agreements made between ninja.
はぁ？ カメだ!? あのな お前➡
The history of man is a history of war.
カメが あの でっけえチャクラの
正体だってのかよ!?
Since the three Great Ninja Wars
うっせえな！ ホントなんだから
しようがねえだろ!!
every nation, and every land
has tried to obtain powerful ninjutsu.
とにかく さっきの津波は
そのカメが起こしたんだってばよ！
Those without power are crushed.
それに アイツを見た ガマ吉のヤツが
三尾だって…。
That is the truth of the ninja world.
The Akatsuki will be branded
as wanted fugitives.
(サクラ)三尾って…
ここに尾獣が出たっていうの!?
Then, not only I,
but the whole world
will hunt Sasuke down.
たぶん… 尻尾の数まで
見たわけじゃねえけど。
Yet you bow your head
for this criminal
and plead for mercy for your friend.
先輩…。
In the ninja world,
that is not friendship!
やっと 連中の狙いが
見えてきたと思ったら➡
また とんでもないものを
引き当てたな。
Boy from the Hidden Leaf,
think hard on what you must do!
とにかく 一度 この霧の
届かないところまで撤退だ。
The ninja world does not indulge fools!
情報を整理して
改めて 今後の策を練る。
Let's go!
Naruto...
Enough already.
Raise your head.
((なぜ 殺さなかったの？))
《紅蓮 : なんだ？ 今のは…》
紅蓮さん…！
幽鬼丸…。
We have been waiting for you.
He's the one.
The old one in the middle.
《そうか
私は 三尾と やりあって➡
意識をなくしてたのか…。
So that's...Danzo!
しかし 三尾の力が
これほどまでとは…。
おそらく 他の連中も
あの激流に巻き込まれたか。
SAMURAI
木ノ葉が動いているとなると➡
早いとこ 麟児たちと
合流しておきたいところだが➡
Please remove your Kage hats.
この霧では…》
三尾のほうは どうなった？
わからない。
LIGHTNING
In response to Lord Raikage's request,
あれから静かになっちゃったし。
そうか。
WATER
In response to Lord Raikage's request,
the five Kage have assembled here.
EARTH
でも よかった。
the five Kage have assembled here.
WIND
紅蓮さんの目が覚めて。
FIRE
ずっと うなされてたんだよ。
いくら呼んでも
全然起きてくれなくて。
I am Mifune, your moderator.
《そうか…。
The Five Kage Summit Conference
is called into order.
コイツ 私が倒れてる間 ずっと…》
じゃあ
とっとと他のヤツらを捜すか。
うん でも どうかな…。
なんだ？
なんだか ヘンなんだ。
体に力が入らなくて…。
お前 また熱が！ いつから？
Naruto's Plea
(ヒナタ)白眼！
I am Mifune, your moderator.
すごい！
(サイ)何か わかりましたか？
The Five Kage Summit Conference
is called into order.
えぇ 戻りましょう。
(サイ)はい。
I shall speak first. Hear me.
There's such a difference
in Kage these days.
(カカシ)どうだった？
To be a Kage at your age
(ヒナタ)はい 確かにあれは
ただの霧じゃありません。
is quite an accomplishment,
Lord Kazekage.
中には かなりのチャクラが
含まれています。
It seems your father trained you
extremely well,
しかも 湖を
まるごと包み込んでいる➡
except in the area of proper etiquette.
かなりのチャクラ量です。
霧は 三尾が
発生させているとみて➡
You're probably right.
間違いなさそうですね。
そうだな。
It is the reason why
I can be here as Kagekaze.
ナルトの話からすると あの霧には
幻覚を見せる力があるようだ。
You certainly are cocky.
Lord Tsuchikage,
there's no need to make fun of him.
ある種の
結界のようなものだろう。
Continue, Lord Kazekage.
湖に近づくのは 危険ですね。
I am a former Jinchuriki.
まずいってばよ！
あの中に まだアイツが！
I was captured by the Akatsuki,
(キバ)アイツって？
サクラちゃん ほら 覚えてんだろ？
- they took my Tailed Beast
-The nerve of that Tsuchikage!
- and nearly killed me.
-Quiet!
ここに来る途中 オレが
知り合いに会ったって言ったこと。
So I consider the Akatsuki
extremely dangerous.
そういえば。
あぁ ナルトの妄想の。
I sought the cooperation of
the five Kage many times,
って 失礼なこと言うな！
とにかく ソイツが湖に…➡
but was ignored.
この霧の中にいるんだってばよ！
Except by the previous Hokage.
湖にね…。
頼む カカシ先生➡
At a time when various lands
have had their Jinchuriki stolen
アイツは 忍者じゃねえんだ。
the response by this group
has been far too slow!
無事かどうか
確かめに行かせてくれ。
残念だが ナルト 許可はできない。
カカシ先生！
How can the Hidden Villages of
the Five Great Nations serve
as an example when they allow
their Jinchuriki to be taken?
お前 さっき
三尾の幻覚にやられ➡
It is an embarrassment!
もう少しで 同士討ちになるところ
だっただろう➡
It is common sense to resolve this
in utmost secrecy.
単独行動は 論外だ。
Seeking the help of other lands
just because of that is nonsense!
それは そうだけどよ。
でもよ カカシ先生➡
Saving face... Prestige...
実際問題
これから どうするんだ？
Such old-fashioned beliefs.
なりゆきとはいえ 大蛇丸の
アジトの探索からは➡
Such a brat.
ずいぶん かけ離れちまったよな。
Old-fashioned beliefs aside...
まぁ 事が
ここまで大きくなると➡
I will acknowledge that as
the Mizukage,
さすがに オレが勝手に
判断していい問題じゃない。
I have delayed action.
ってことで すでに パックンを
木ノ葉に走らせてある。
However, having our Tailed Beast
stolen is no cause for immediate fear.
綱手様の指示が来るまで
オレたちは ここで待機だ。
Controlling a Tailed Beast requires
skill, knowledge and time.
(カカシ)しばらくは 霧の外側から
連中と三尾の動きを監視する。
The Jinchuriki and the Tailed Beast
must mature together
and adapt to each other.
いいな。
はい。
(パックン)ということじゃ。
And still, controlling
the Tailed Beast is difficult.
(綱手)三尾は 先の大戦のなか➡
It is not a simple task.
Isn't that so, Lord Kazekage?
行方知れずになったと
聞いていたが➡
こんな形で現れるとは。
The only ones who were capable
of controlling a Tailed Beast were
(パックン)大蛇丸のヤツ➡
やっかいなものに
手を出しおったもんじゃ。
Madara Uchiha and
the First Hokage, Senju Hashirama.
(シズネ)ですが 尾獣は 暁が
血眼になって探しているはず➡
Also Fourth Mizukage Yagura,
and Lord Raikage's younger brother,
Killer Bee.
我々が 先に発見できたのは
不幸中の幸いかもしれません。
However...
- Chojuro!
- Right!
そうだな。
このうえ 暁の耳に入れば➡
Enough...
三つ巴の
泥仕合になることは確実。
of this!
誰にも 渡すわけにはいかない。
This is a place of discussion.
では 捕獲を？
Please refrain from disruptive actions.
容易ではなさそうだがな。
(綱手)しかし 前例がない
というわけでもあるまい。
Stand down, Foo, Torune.
You too, Kankuro, Temari.
私は 過去の文献をあたる。
Ao, Chojuro. I'm fine.
お前は その間に
そこに書いてあるメンバーを招集しろ。
Yes, ma'am.
了解しました。
(いの)フゥ～ 終わった。
今日は あなたが来てくれて
助かったわ。
Let us continue our discussion.
ホントですか？
ええ これからも がんばってね。
The Hidden Leaf, Rock, Sand and Mist...
Rogue Ninja from your villages
make up the Akatsuki!
はい！
And that is not all!
(テンテン)ハァ ハァ これ以上はムリよ。
From our investigations,
we know that among you,
including your previous Kage,
there are those who used the Akatsuki!
これからですよ テンテン。
(リー)これからが 本当の勝負です。
Used them?!
(ガイ)よく言ったぞ リー。 ハッハッ。
I do not trust you!
I had no intention of even
discussing this with you.
青春に弱音は禁物だ テンテン。
But the reason I convened this summit
そうですよ。 仲間とは 常に
お互いを意識し➡
is to question your loyalty!
その背中を守り合うもの。
お互い 体術を極めた者同士➡
What do you mean, "used" the Akatsuki?
無敵のコンビネーションを
手に入れようじゃありませんか。
You are the Kazekage,
yet you have not been informed?
だから アンタのスタンドプレーに
振り回されて➡
Ask the elders back home!
疲れが倍化してんのよ。
You used the Akatsuki in the past war!
ウム リーよ。 この修業の目的は何だ？
味方同士の連携。
The Great Nations are heading
towards uniform stability.
つまり あうんの呼吸を
つかみ合う修業… です。
They are moving from military expansion
to military disarmament.
そうだ。 だが 今 お前は
テンテンと呼吸が合ってると思うか？
As fear and the threat of war
diminishes between nations,
あっ。
(テンテン)ハァ ハァ…。
Hidden Villages, which are
the source of its military strength,
《息が荒い。 しまった》
become costly hindrances.
わかりました ガイ先生。
And yet, carelessly downsizing
the villages poses a risk.
ボクの気持が先走りすぎたようです。
さすがオレの教え子だ。
のみ込みが早い。
What if war suddenly breaks out?
だいたい こんな調子で
５時間ぶっ続けじゃ➡
It would be a problem to
depend on ninja
who have no experience in war.
いくつ体があっても
もたないわよ。
It would mean certain defeat!
ボクは まだまだやれますよ。
(ガイ)よく言った リーよ。
And one way to reduce that risk is
mercenary soldiers.
では テンテンの息が整い次第
修業再開だ。
オレの体術で
容赦なく攻撃するから➡
Namely, the Akatsuki?
全力で回避し受け止めてみせろ。
オッス ガイ先生！
えぇ～。
《ハァ 結局まだやるのか》
(テンテン)ちょっと待って あれ。
(リー)招集… ですか？
It takes effort and money to train
skilled ninja from your own village.
(ガイ)よし 続きは帰ってからだ。
いってこい ２人とも。
熱き血潮をたぎらせて
修業の成果を見せつけてやれ！
But the Akatsuki,
which makes war its livelihood,
is made up of experienced professionals.
オッス。
はい。
Furthermore, they can be hired
for cheap.
と まあ おおまかな説明は以上だ。
Best of all,
they return exceptional results.
(綱手)これより お前たちには➡
先に出発したカカシたちの
サポートに回ってもらう。
Get serious, Tsuchikage!
わかっていると思うが 最優先
なのは三尾を封印することだ。
The Sand used the Akatsuki
to destroy the Hidden Leaf.
(シズネ)封印には繊細な
チャクラコントロールが必要になるわ。
I'm speaking of Orochimaru!
It is not clear if he had broken away
from the Akatsuki or not.
医療忍者である 私と いの。
現地にいるサクラとヒナタで
封印班を組む予定よ。
But as a result, your father,
the Fourth Kazekage,
and the Third Hokage Hiruzen, died.
はい がんばります。
リーとテンテンには ヒナタとサクラが
抜けた穴を埋めてもらいたい。
And frankly, it's hard not to
rule out the idea
敵が三尾を狙っている以上
戦闘は避けられんだろうからな。
that this was someone's scheme.
任せてください。
青春フルパワーで戦ってみせますよ。
The old fox.
The most suspicious is the Hidden Mist!
現地までは ワシが案内する。
皆 遅れるなよ！
You Mist do not conduct diplomacy.
There are even rumors that
the Akatsuki originated there!
Since we have come this far
I will speak honestly.
《ったく 他人の看病して 自分が
倒れちゃ 話にならないだろ》
Is Lady Fifth going to reveal...
There were suspicions that
someone was manipulating Yagura,
our Fourth Mizukage.
《コイツの面倒を見るのは
２回目だな》
And there was a possibility that
it was the Akatsuki.
((紅蓮 : そんな量を飲ませたら…))
No one wanted this to
get blown out of proportion.
《もしかしたら
あの薬のせいなのか？》
Each and every one of you...
《とにかく コイツを連れて➡
Hold your tongue, Raikage!
敵と戦闘になるようなことは
避けないと》
Ultimately, it is because your village
disregarded the disarmament efforts
ゴホッ ゴホゴホッ。
and sought powerful ninjutsu.
おい 幽鬼丸 しっかりしろ！
We had no choice but to counter
by hiring the Akatsuki!
あの… ね…➡
紅蓮さんが…
ボクの帰る場所… なんだ…。
What?!
Before we start arguing
about the situation,
えっ？
there is a statement
I have been waiting to make.
やっと… 見つけた…。
What is it?
The leader of the Akatsuki is...
probably Madara Uchiha.
《もう… みんな 交代で
見張りしてるっていうのに➡
ナルトのヤツ！》
Are you sure of that?
Hasn't he been dead for several decades?
He is right.
He died long ago.
I do not know the details.
But the information is quite reliable.
何さぼってんのよ。
Are you saying he is immortal?!
サクラちゃん…。
Perhaps.
オレ… ずっと考えてたんだ…。
To think...that he was really a monster.
けど… １人じゃ
答えが見つからなくて…。
この間 修業の時…➡
I want to speak on behalf
of the neutral nations.
エロ仙人が言ってたんだ…。
自来也様が？
The leader of the Akatsuki was
able to read the times well.
「思っている人がいるところが
帰る場所」なんだって…。
Despite stabilization,
nations had private suspicions
ステキな言葉…。
and the Akatsuki took advantage
of that weakness to amass its power.
それって… ホントに
そうなのかな… って…。
What are you trying to say?!
もし そうなら
こっちが思い続ければ➡
Calm down.
Turn calamity into good fortune.
ソイツは帰ってくるってことだろ…。
It is extremely rare for all
five Kage to assemble.
What do you say?
そうね… そうであってほしい
と思うけど…。
Until the Akatsuki is eliminated,
why not establish
the world's first Allied Shinobi Forces
of the Five Hidden Villages?
どんなに思ってたって…
帰ってこない人はいる…。
思いを伝えるのって…
すごく難しいことだよね…。
An allied force?
That is a fine plan.
We are in an emergency state.
だからって… 伝えることを
あきらめちまったら…。
Cooperation is crucial.
思ってくれる人が
いなくなったら…。
つれえよな…。
It's going perfectly.
確かに… 私たちが
あきらめちゃったら…。
Going forward, we must determine
a chain of command.
本当に帰る場所が
なくなっちゃうものね。
We must avoid any further confusion.
そうよ！ 誰がなんと言おうと➡
So? Who will we choose to
lead the allied forces?
私たちが思い続けることで…➡
いつでも気楽に帰れる場所を
作っておかなくちゃ！
サクラちゃん…。
Leaving that to you five
will only result in arguments.
…なんてね。
So I ask that you respect
the position of the neutral nations
そうだよな…。 やっぱ オレたちが➡
and allow me to come up
with a proposal
あきらめるわけには
いかねえよな… うん！
サクラちゃんのおかげで
すっきりしたってばよ！
じゃ 私 そろそろ持ち場に戻る。
30分もしたら
次のツーマンセルが交代に来るから➡
アンタも しっかり見張りなさいよ。
サンキュー… サクラちゃん。
そうだよな…。
((じゃあ 誰かが
ボクのことを思ってくれたら➡
(そこが ボクの
帰る場所になるんだね))
《そうだ… 誰が なんと言おうと
思い続ければいい》
《でもって…
アイツが本当に帰る場所…➡
ないんなら…
オレが帰る場所になってやる！》